CHRISTIAN ANDERSON, MBA

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

christian.p.anderson1@gmail.com 303-946-5386

LINKEDIN

linkedin.com/in/christian-p-anderson

PORTFOLIO

andersonchristian-p.github.io

GITHUB

github.com/AndersonChristian-P

LOCATION

Denver, CO (willing to relocate)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript / ES6
 SQL
- HTML5
- CSS3 Agile
- ReactJS • MS Office

Git

Node

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development DevMountain 2019

MBA

University of Alaska Anchorage 1998 - 2002

Bachelor's - Biological Sciences University of Alaska Fairbanks 1992 - 1997

SUMMARY

Front-End Web Developer with expertise in modern tech stack. UI / UX web design award recognition. Over 18 years of professional experience working collaboratively in teams. Deep interest in efficiency, team building, communication, and work ethics.

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

DevMountain - Web Developer

2019

Hiut Clone | hiut-clone.happycoder.io

Cloned the major features of Hiut Denim's eCommerce site to learn how to apply the technology to an eCommerce platform.

- HTML5, Sass, CSS3, JavaScript, Axios, ReactJS, Redux, Stripe for the stylings and functionality on the front-end.
- Node, Express, Massive, SQL for handling requests and database for the backend. **BcryptJS** for authentication.
- Built RESTful APIs in JavaScript and Express.
- NodeMailer to send a password reset link via email.
- Amazon S3 to host product and collateral images.
- Incorporated responsive design.

EXPERIENCE

Vertafore - Customer Support Specialist I

Jan 2020 - Present

Denver, CO

- Deliver a best effort to answer or resolve a Customer query or issue on the first contact.
- Produce clear and concise documentation on Customer reported issues, and subsequent resolution.
- Complete other duties as assigned by manager.

Accenture Flex - Digital Media Support Specialist Oct 2019 - Dec 2019 Denver, CO

- Addressed Zendesk tickets to provide pre- and post-sales support for Accenture client Snap Ad self-service product.
- Streamlined support ticket response process with a modularized workflow.

IKEA - Prep & Flow

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

Centennial, CO

Mastered mobile technology to determine product floor locations and process products for warehouse assignment.

PRO IS, Inc. - Underwriting Assistant

May - Oct 2018

York, PA

- Reviewed accounts to ensure adherence to quality standards.
- Leveraged technology to surpass weekly production goals.

United States Postal Service - Mail Processing Clerk Nov 2016 - Oct 2017 Boulder, CO

- Managed ever changing priorities daily.
- At the peak of the holiday season, I took the initiative and leveraged team personnel to increase our package sortation efficiency by 25%.

CHRISTIAN ANDERSON, MBA

EXPERIENCE

Penamora Photo - Freelance Photographer Westminster, CO

Jul 2012 - Nov 2016

- Continually interacted with customers to understand their needs. I utilized these stories to improve my work processes and product offerings.
- Processed, cataloged, and optimized digital images for the web with Adobe Photoshop and Lightroom.

BP - Financial Analyst

May 2001 - Feb 2012

Anchorage, AK

- Streamlined my department's close process, resulting in an average reduction of 20% of time spent on close.
- Mentored finance and engineering staff.
- Through continued study and work outcomes, awarded designation as a subject matter expert in the finance elements of estimation and categorization of reserves and resources.